# Abhi Bhyravajjula

M.S. Energy Systems Engineering B.Tech. (Hon.) Mechanical Engineering



## **Professional Summary**

Multifaceted **Developer & Engineering Manager** with **6+** years of experience in C&I and utility scale solar development, estimation, & construction and interconnection. Subject Matter Expert in leading and managing all aspects of project development from site feasibility & acquisition to turnkey end point handoff to client. Experienced in the development of projects in NE ISO and NYISO markets including the EPC (Engineering, Permitting, and Construction) processes and financial structuring of large renewable energy assets deals and contracts. Most recently established a department including processes, infrastructure, & company-wide training, generating a 70MW+ solar project pipeline valued over \$100 Million over a period of 1.5 years. Thorough professional who excels at client and stakeholder engagement throughout the project lifecycle. Worked with a broad spectrum of clientele ranging from small businesses to Fortune 500 enterprises focusing on on-site generation, community distributed generation, and standalone systems. Passionate about making a difference in the world through sustainable energy technologies as we transition into more localized grids and energy markets.

## Skills

- Systems Design & Development
- Project Management
- Energy Systems Design | Analysis
- Helioscope, PVSyst, AutoCAD
- Salesforce | Procore
- Financial | Cost | Incentive Analysis
- Procurement
- Advanced Excel Data Analysis (Visual Basic, SQL)
- OSHA 10 Certified
- Energy Incentives State & Federal

- Project Estimation
- Project Permitting
- Local Zoning Laws, Fire Code, NEC Code
- Contract & Proposal Drafting
- Digital Marketing & Lead Generation
- Client Outreach & Engagement
- Microsoft Office & Google Workspace
- Microsoft Power BI
- Planning & Logistics
- Multilingual: French, Telugu, Hindi

## **Work Experience**

#### February 2022 - Present: Worcester, MA | Hybrid

## Sr. Solar Developer | Director / World Energy | XL Fleet

- Actively manages all departments related to the development process including Engineering, Project Finance, Procurement, Sales, and Project Management while developing and overseeing a 70 MW and growing pipeline of solar projects valued at over \$100 Million.
- Leads all aspects of project development including scheduling and budgeting creating visibility to the executive management team. Typical projects sizes range from 0.5MW-DC to 25MW-DC in the Northeast markets.
- Engages all key internal and external stakeholders, decisionmakers, and subcontractors to adhere to deadlines and complete projects on or under budget.
- Actively manages the end-to-end development cycle including the engineering, permitting, procurement, site
  logistics, and construction of turnkey solar and solar + storage opportunities focusing specifically on the NE ISO
  and NYISO markets.
- Created pricing tools, process-flow charts, contract templates, and other relevant infrastructure required to successfully engage and manage a large pipeline of Solar energy projects from point of origination to utility permission-to-operate.
- Excels at project estimation, bid and RFP submittals, and contract negotiation interacting with the utility and relevant AHJs as required.

#### September 2021 - February 2022: Boston MA | Remote

### Sr. Engineer (Solar) / Solect Energy

- Develop complete engineering and permitting package from project inception to construction ready documentation for commercial and utility grade solar projects on the East Coast.
- Act as technical expert for client throughout the project lifecycle including feasibility, design, structural analysis, permitting, interconnection, and construction.
- Mentor junior engineers and provide interdepartmental communication and updates as the project manager.
- Actively improve functional process and workflow aspects for the design and engineering team

#### April 2021 - August 2021: Chino CA | Remote

## Regional Manager, North America / NE Solar | ZNShine Solar

- Oversee the manufacturing process of high efficiency modules in offshore manufacturing plants with a total production capacity of 1.5 GW.
- Work on the forefront of client-sided procurement and establishing Master-Supply agreements with large commercial and utility scale developers.
- Actively guide clients through the procurement process and be the technical expert on module technology.
- Expertise in logistics for international and inland shipping, industry & market trends, and contractual language.

## January 2021 – March 2021: San Diego CA | Remote

### Sr. Project Manager / Cal Solar

- Oversee and engineer the design & build of commercial scale solar PV, solar thermal, and energy storage. solutions with projects ranging from 50kW-2MW for multifamily residential and commercial buildings in CA.
- Manage a team of design engineers from various trades including mechanical, electrical, and structural.
- Actively involved through all stages of the project lifecycle and assisting clients with interconnection.
- Engage clients with out-of-the box solutions for design and construction related problems.
- As part of the core management team, provide constant advice for process improvement.
- Act as the final barrier for quality control before designs are moved into construction.

## December 2019 - January 2021: New York City, NY

#### Project Manager (Solar), On-Site Generation | BrightPower

- Design solar PV projects ranging from 50kW-5MW for multifamily residential and commercial buildings in New York and New Jersey regions
- Coordinate with engineers, architects, vendors, general contractors, developers, and sub-contractors throughout project lifecycle.
- Actively manage several on-site generation projects and act as point of contact throughout project lifecycle for all involved stakeholders.
- Draft designs for PV systems (mechanical and electrical) incorporating local law, energy policy & incentives, zoning & regulations, and actively oversee permitting process.
- Conducting shading and zoning studies to ensure project feasibility; Perform Feasibility Studies.
- Total solar designed 26MW, Total solar installed 6MW.

## **Education**

#### September 2015-December 2017: Boston, Massachusetts

## Master of Science Energy Systems Engineering / Northeastern University

• Core Competencies: Energy systems design & analysis, Solar and Battery Energy Systems, Sustainable design & planning, Energy modeling, Project Finance, Urban planning, Energy Policy, Project management

#### September 2011-April 2015: Hyderabad, India

## Bachelor of Technology (Honors) Mechanical Engineering / GITAM University

• Core Competencies: Thermal systems design & analysis, Machine design, Computer aided design & manufacturing, HVAC design & efficiency analysis, Renewable energy integration